# **JASON THOMPSON**

# DATA ANALYST

931-607-5620 | Email Jason | GitHub Account | LinkedIn Profile

#### **SUMMARY**

Logical Data Analyst with a passion for extracting statements and facts from raw data and turning them into useful information. Experience producing intelligence to enhance business planning and operations. Activates strong analytical skills to investigate trends in large amounts of data and formulate conclusions based on findings. Highly successful at leveraging data trends and patterns.

#### SKILLS

- Analytical Problem Solving
- Data Quality
- Query and Reporting Tools
- Data Analysis
- Excel
- Tableau
- PostgreSQL

- Python
- Clear and Concise Communication
- · Data Visualization and Presentations
- Power BI
- Power Pivot

#### DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

#### 1/2022 - 6/2022 NSS DATA ANALYST APPRENTICE

Nashville Software School - NASHVILLE, TN

Intensive part-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI —<u>Tableau Workshop</u>, PowerBI Workshop
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn GDP and Internet
  Usage Project
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium Geospatial Python Project
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy <u>Data Analyst</u> <u>Jobs Dataset</u>

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 1/2020 - 12/2021 HANDYMAN APPRENTICE

#### Shane Self: Self-Reliance - COOKEVILLE, TN

- Trained in/executed numerous remodeling style tasks in residential and commercial environments
- · Maintained organization, cleanliness, and safety in work areas
- Shadowed craft experts and supervisors to learn wide range of simple and complex techniques

#### 2/2020 - 1/2021 TECHNICAL WRITER

#### Vertical Lift Consulting – MURFREESBORO, TN

- Revised and updated numerous documents used for training and instructional purposes
- Extensive training in InDesign, InCopy, Acrobat, Photoshop, Illustrator
- Trained in script types such as XML and JSON

### 5/2018 - 11/2018 LEAD VEHICLE SERVICE AGENT: 7/2018 - 11/2018

Fleetlogix - NASHVILLE, TN

- Trained new service agents (employees)
- Assigned agents to workstations appropriately for productivity, safety, and efficiency
- Assisted agents in cleaning duties to achieve daily goals
- Addressed various production obstacles that agents would encounter

# **VEHICLE SERVICE AGENT: 5/2018 - 7/2018**

- Tasks included servicing returned rental cars for re-distribution such as:
- Inspecting fuel levels, tire pressure, damages, cleanliness (internal and external), etc.
- Quickly satisfying needs of inspected areas found lacking

# 1/2017 - 8/2017 L1 TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST

Servpro Industries, Inc. – GALLATIN, TN

- Delivered local and remote Tier 1 IT support for hardware and software to company personnel
- Assisted customers in US and Canada with various types of technical issues via email, remote session, and phone
- Documented repair processes and helped streamline procedures for future technical support actions
- Devised incisive workarounds and resolutions for IT-related problems

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Graduation Expected APPRENTICESHIP: DATA ANALYST

in 6/2022 Nashville Software School – Nashville, TN

12/2015 B.B.A: COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Middle Tennessee State University - Murfreesboro, TN